<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - community</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www.ourworld.tf/categories/community/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www.ourworld.tf"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/categories/community/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet that connects us also manipulates us. In search of a better future.</title>
		<published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/04/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/04/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet is one of humanity’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincodex.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;14083&#x2F;threefold-host-the-cloud-at-your-house&#x2F;&quot;&gt;greatest inventions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In its early days, it used to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;web-3-0-the-decentralised-web-promises-to-make-the-internet-free-again-113139&quot;&gt;free and decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by nature. No single entity was able to control access to the web as it was built on the foundation of a peer-to-peer network of nodes owned by developers and researchers. Until the dot-com era. Throughout the early 2000s, large corporations took over the web. New platforms like YouTube and MySpace were launched and new infrastructure needed to be built at an extreme pace, starting the data revolution and changing the digital landscape forever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years down the line, the Internet’s architecture has become highly centralized – owned by a handful of large corporations that act as the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.newyorker.com&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;2017&#x2F;08&#x2F;28&#x2F;who-owns-the-internet&quot;&gt;gatekeepers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our digital world. What was once an open and free platform accessible to anyone has long since built up barriers and lost its neutrality. Users are trapped in a cyberspace that exploits their personal data and allows censorship, hate speech, disinformation and political targeting to thrive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Going down the Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wsj.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;the-facebook-files-11631713039&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; “The Facebook Files” and The New York Times’ audio series “&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;22&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;rabbit-hole-prologue.html&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” are only some of the latest examples that depict the shocking impacts of the manipulation, mental health problems, and extremism that social media algorithms are fuelling. Nevertheless, these incidents are only a glimpse into all the ways we’re being affected and influenced about the way we see the world – by the tech giants and their algorithms. Tech giants like Google and Facebook have been surrounded by a constant stream of data privacy &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;story&#x2F;should-big-tech-own-our-personal-data&#x2F;&quot;&gt;scandals&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as more and more whistleblowers expose their misconduct. However, there are plenty of other, hidden players using the tools and algorithms of social media platforms for their own agendas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;filmthreat.com&#x2F;features&#x2F;4-thought-provoking-movies-on-digital-privacy-and-security&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Great Hack and the Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are great documentaries that shed light on how the Internet as we know it became compromised. They depict how algorithms are used to mine user data, control information feeds and manipulate our digital experiences. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.politico.eu&#x2F;article&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-chris-wylie-brexit-trump-britain-data-protection-privacy-facebook&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trump Election and the Brexit vote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were heavily influenced by private companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;series&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-files&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that manipulated mass audiences through social media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By purchasing thousands of personal data points collected by social media platforms and analyzing them, companies like Cambridge Analytica are able to not only predict but influence the behaviour of each and everyone of us. Data collection and analysis to such an extent allow these companies to craft and push perfectly targeted messages to users in a way that’s optimized to sway their opinions in favour of whatever agenda they have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot;&gt;Can a neutral and free Internet still exist?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 24th of March 2022, the European Parliament and Council negotiators agreed upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;digital&#x2F;global&#x2F;facebook-google-amazon-apple-digital-market-act-europe-regulation-1235214516&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Digital Markets Act&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DMA). It seeks to give users more choice by demanding the most popular apps to open up and interoperate with smaller apps. Moreover, the act aims to ensure a fairer market competition by prohibiting certain gatekeeper practices like self-preferencing and targeted advertising. This set of new EU regulations is likely to impact the daily business of tech giants significantly once it becomes law. While the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.europarl.europa.eu&#x2F;news&#x2F;en&#x2F;press-room&#x2F;20220315IPR25504&#x2F;deal-on-digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-competition-and-more-choice-for-users&quot;&gt;DMA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; promises to mitigate some of the issues discussed, it is doubtful that the act will be enough to fundamentally change the current system. This is a step in the right direction, but much more needs to be done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become our digital home. It’s impacting our lives in many ways by creating new opportunities, and changing how we communicate and connect. Therefore, it is crucial to restore the Internet’s neutrality to ensure a fair and equal environment. We need an Internet where we can rely on data security and privacy. An Internet where we’re empowered to truly and completely have ownership of and control of our own data. An Internet that empowers us with digital sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet used to be a free movement of culture and the Web. It started with an open-source and peer-to-peer vision to connect people. And while Web 3.0 projects are looking to liberalize the Internet as we know it, most of them still rely on centralized Web 2.0 infrastructure to some degree. The world needs better, holistic solutions. ThreeFold is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realizing the initial vision and promise&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer planetary mesh network of nodes owned by humanity. It’s a 100% open-source and community-driven project that builds the critical, neutral infrastructure for a decentralized world – one that is built and owned by the people. With ThreeFold, individuals and organizations are empowered to store their data and run their applications on a peer-to-peer network of nodes in a way that ensures their data will not be manipulated, hacked or lost.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by a global community, ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure with a few thousand 3Nodes connected from 74 countries and the neutral foundation for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;any current and future IT workload&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. ThreeFold is now on the verge of opening up a new Internet era free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. And anyone can participate in ThreeFold’s model by building or buying a 3Node, and connecting Internet capacity from their home or office – creating a fully &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break free from big tech and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-Realizing the Promise</title>
		<published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was once a massive global movement sparked by the idealism of free culture and the net, is now hosting a wave of unintended consequences that may destroy sovereignty and freedom as we know it. The digital revolution and the “democratization” of the Internet promised to lead us to a prosperous and equitable world, one that brought us closer together, eliminating both physical and virtual boundaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are creating a world that all may enter without privilege or prejudice accorded by race, economic power, military force, or station of birth… a world where anyone, anywhere may express his or her beliefs, no matter how singular, without fear of being coerced into silence or conformity… Your legal concepts of property, expression, identity, movement, and context do not apply to us. They are all based on matter, and there is no matter here.” – Declaration of independence of Cyberspace – John Perry Barlow – Davos, 1996.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the world we live in today. Borders are hardening in our virtual world with the Great Firewall of China and the widespread emergence of Internet “clusters”. Many countries have attempted to turn off Internet services or to prevent free speech. Networks and algorithms turn us into data generators, influencing our daily habits and interests. It’s turning into a big AI-driven machine that commoditizes our lives, leaves the underserved behind and fails to provide sovereignty where we gather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. The technology that connects us is now used to distract, manipulate, polarize, divide and control the way we think, act and live our lives. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of people and IoT devices expected to join this broken digital world this decade, we have no choice but to heal our broken information ecosystem if we want to address the challenges we face collectively. So as we move towards a world where tech and science are merging together, how do we ensure a neutral, inclusive and regenerative digital future – one that truly serves humanity and eliminates the barriers that divide us?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer Internet incentivizes all citizens of our world to connect computers from their homes or offices to participate in a distributed data economy owned by the people. By allowing humans and machines to interweave without intermediaries, a decentralized and self-sovereign Internet can emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply – there is no good reason that our data is being stored and controlled by others in the information age. Why are we paying centralized companies to handle our information on our behalf, when it makes us vulnerable to be turned into products, and would take us the same time to do it ourselves?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer isn’t an alternative to the Internet, it’s an alternative to centralized cloud giants. The Internet doesn’t need replacing; it is one of the most beautiful inventions of our civilization, if not the greatest. Which is not to say that cloud providers are completely obsolete. They serve functions that decentralized systems cannot (e.g. big data); but peer-to-peer systems are just infinitely more resilient, secure, private and scalable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of exponential evolution and innovation, we have our fears around the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to disconnect ourselves even further from our reality and it is our responsibility to ensure a safe and fair future for the generations to come. A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential of technology to change the world remains endless and limited to our own imagination. We decide to switch from fear to love, and to move forward as one humanity. It is our responsibility as global citizens to pursue greater collective consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movement, a community of like-minded people that build the world of tomorrow!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;host the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Into the Fold – The ThreeFold Movement</title>
		<published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/07/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/07/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s not by mistake that you&#x27;re here, reading this post. You, like I, understand that today&#x27;s systems need to change. You know that decentralization is needed for better wealth distribution and equal opportunities. And that we need better solutions for our planet. You can feel that a global shift is happening. And you want to do something about it. You want to be a part of it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You&#x27;ve dreamt of a different world. A world where people trust and treat each other with respect – and where everyone has equal chances to learn and to thrive. A world where we&#x27;re not just cogs in a machine that serves only the few, rather we work and co-create as part of systems that benefit all. A world where solutions are sustainable for our planet, or even better, regenerative. This world is not just a dream, though – and you&#x27;re not alone. Each day, more and more like-minded people are coming together. Welcome into the fold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-the-movement&quot;&gt;Meet the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand ThreeFold, you should first understand where we came from. Since the late 90&#x27;s, some of the ThreeFold co-founders have worked on Internet storage and cloud technology. And after years of building, and many successful launches, they came to understand that they were part of a broken system that was productizing people and damaging the planet. Despite this, they knew that the Internet held and holds the key to a better world, and that the only way to have a truly sovereign, secure, and energy-efficient Internet was to start from scratch. So we did.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is how our story began – and over the past four years we have grown and expanded a team of like-minded and passionate people from around the world to bring ThreeFold to life. But for us, we are still in the beginning of something much bigger to come.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We don&#x27;t consider ourselves a company, rather a group of humans helping other humans – and our planet. We believe the world needs to change, and we choose to not just talk, but act, to make that change happen. We cannot and would not want to do this alone. There is a strong, passionate, and growing community around us – partners, farmers, ambassadors, technology testers, other contributors, and supporters just like you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission-vision-and-values-drive-us-forward&quot;&gt;Our Mission, Vision, and Values Drive us Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to build and expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet owned by the people, for the people. This will enable equal chances for people around the world to learn, partake and succeed, and will help to heal our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Engrained into the work that we do are three key values or principles:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and in protecting people. Everyone should own their data, and no one else, not even ThreeFold. Our peer-to-peer technology allows every user to be data sovereign – giving them 100% control over their data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that everyone should be given &lt;strong&gt;equal chances&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to learn, partake and succeed. Internet access is a human right, and at ThreeFold we commit to scale our technology to new regions to empower the unconnected.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we unify our practices, partnerships, and products around a single mission – to &lt;strong&gt;heal our planet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. By making our technology actionable, we enable a collective approach to have an impact together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;together-we-invite-the-world-into-the-fold&quot;&gt;Together, We Invite the World Into the Fold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s important for others to understand who we are. Thus, we identify with and embody three key attributes as a collective, to show the world what the movement is all about:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is purposeful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We exist to help humanity thrive. Our mission is bold and motivates every step we take. We adapt to our evolving environment and passionately strive for excellence.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is empowering.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We help people find themselves and do what they love. We provide support to people and projects that help build a better world, whether they have moonshot visions or down-to-earth ambitions. We aren’t the hero of our story – they are.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is approachable.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold keeps it real. We’re open and honest, avoiding upstage corporate language and phony marketing spins. We don’t see ourselves as a company, but more like humans helping other humans. So being genuine, friendly, and loving comes naturally.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In its essence, the movement is open and inviting. We&#x27;ve created &lt;strong&gt;a participatory Internet economy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where anybody around the world can plug in a 3Node and add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we&#x27;re expanding a data sovereign and planet positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people, across geographical and cultural borders.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;collaboration, not competition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our technology serves as a responsible underlying layer on top of which anybody can build and create. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;beautiful partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; already on board – and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;an alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of conscious people and organizations who share our vision – and we are constantly expanding our ecosystem across industries.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And while the ThreeFold Foundation is currently the driving force behind the ThreeFold Movement, we believe in &lt;strong&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We have open channels like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;a forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;a two-way Telegram chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Github (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where people can and do contribute, ask questions and provide feedback that goes into our everyday decision-making and actions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As I said at the start, you&#x27;ve dreamt of a different world. And so have I. John Lennon once said, &amp;quot;A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.&amp;quot; Thank you for dreaming with us. Together, this will happen!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
