<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - farming</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www.ourworld.tf/categories/farming/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www.ourworld.tf"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/categories/farming/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet that connects us also manipulates us. In search of a better future.</title>
		<published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/04/post-10/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/04/post-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet is one of humanity’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincodex.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;14083&#x2F;threefold-host-the-cloud-at-your-house&#x2F;&quot;&gt;greatest inventions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In its early days, it used to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;web-3-0-the-decentralised-web-promises-to-make-the-internet-free-again-113139&quot;&gt;free and decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by nature. No single entity was able to control access to the web as it was built on the foundation of a peer-to-peer network of nodes owned by developers and researchers. Until the dot-com era. Throughout the early 2000s, large corporations took over the web. New platforms like YouTube and MySpace were launched and new infrastructure needed to be built at an extreme pace, starting the data revolution and changing the digital landscape forever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years down the line, the Internet’s architecture has become highly centralized – owned by a handful of large corporations that act as the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.newyorker.com&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;2017&#x2F;08&#x2F;28&#x2F;who-owns-the-internet&quot;&gt;gatekeepers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our digital world. What was once an open and free platform accessible to anyone has long since built up barriers and lost its neutrality. Users are trapped in a cyberspace that exploits their personal data and allows censorship, hate speech, disinformation and political targeting to thrive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Going down the Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wsj.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;the-facebook-files-11631713039&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; “The Facebook Files” and The New York Times’ audio series “&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;22&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;rabbit-hole-prologue.html&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” are only some of the latest examples that depict the shocking impacts of the manipulation, mental health problems, and extremism that social media algorithms are fuelling. Nevertheless, these incidents are only a glimpse into all the ways we’re being affected and influenced about the way we see the world – by the tech giants and their algorithms. Tech giants like Google and Facebook have been surrounded by a constant stream of data privacy &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;story&#x2F;should-big-tech-own-our-personal-data&#x2F;&quot;&gt;scandals&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as more and more whistleblowers expose their misconduct. However, there are plenty of other, hidden players using the tools and algorithms of social media platforms for their own agendas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;filmthreat.com&#x2F;features&#x2F;4-thought-provoking-movies-on-digital-privacy-and-security&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Great Hack and the Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are great documentaries that shed light on how the Internet as we know it became compromised. They depict how algorithms are used to mine user data, control information feeds and manipulate our digital experiences. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.politico.eu&#x2F;article&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-chris-wylie-brexit-trump-britain-data-protection-privacy-facebook&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trump Election and the Brexit vote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were heavily influenced by private companies like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;series&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-files&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that manipulated mass audiences through social media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By purchasing thousands of personal data points collected by social media platforms and analyzing them, companies like Cambridge Analytica are able to not only predict but influence the behaviour of each and everyone of us. Data collection and analysis to such an extent allow these companies to craft and push perfectly targeted messages to users in a way that’s optimized to sway their opinions in favour of whatever agenda they have.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot;&gt;Can a neutral and free Internet still exist?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 24th of March 2022, the European Parliament and Council negotiators agreed upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;digital&#x2F;global&#x2F;facebook-google-amazon-apple-digital-market-act-europe-regulation-1235214516&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Digital Markets Act&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DMA). It seeks to give users more choice by demanding the most popular apps to open up and interoperate with smaller apps. Moreover, the act aims to ensure a fairer market competition by prohibiting certain gatekeeper practices like self-preferencing and targeted advertising. This set of new EU regulations is likely to impact the daily business of tech giants significantly once it becomes law. While the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.europarl.europa.eu&#x2F;news&#x2F;en&#x2F;press-room&#x2F;20220315IPR25504&#x2F;deal-on-digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-competition-and-more-choice-for-users&quot;&gt;DMA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; promises to mitigate some of the issues discussed, it is doubtful that the act will be enough to fundamentally change the current system. This is a step in the right direction, but much more needs to be done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become our digital home. It’s impacting our lives in many ways by creating new opportunities, and changing how we communicate and connect. Therefore, it is crucial to restore the Internet’s neutrality to ensure a fair and equal environment. We need an Internet where we can rely on data security and privacy. An Internet where we’re empowered to truly and completely have ownership of and control of our own data. An Internet that empowers us with digital sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet used to be a free movement of culture and the Web. It started with an open-source and peer-to-peer vision to connect people. And while Web 3.0 projects are looking to liberalize the Internet as we know it, most of them still rely on centralized Web 2.0 infrastructure to some degree. The world needs better, holistic solutions. ThreeFold is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realizing the initial vision and promise&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer planetary mesh network of nodes owned by humanity. It’s a 100% open-source and community-driven project that builds the critical, neutral infrastructure for a decentralized world – one that is built and owned by the people. With ThreeFold, individuals and organizations are empowered to store their data and run their applications on a peer-to-peer network of nodes in a way that ensures their data will not be manipulated, hacked or lost.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by a global community, ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure with a few thousand 3Nodes connected from 74 countries and the neutral foundation for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;any current and future IT workload&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. ThreeFold is now on the verge of opening up a new Internet era free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. And anyone can participate in ThreeFold’s model by building or buying a 3Node, and connecting Internet capacity from their home or office – creating a fully &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break free from big tech and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;post&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-Realizing the Promise</title>
		<published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-8/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-8/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was once a massive global movement sparked by the idealism of free culture and the net, is now hosting a wave of unintended consequences that may destroy sovereignty and freedom as we know it. The digital revolution and the “democratization” of the Internet promised to lead us to a prosperous and equitable world, one that brought us closer together, eliminating both physical and virtual boundaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are creating a world that all may enter without privilege or prejudice accorded by race, economic power, military force, or station of birth… a world where anyone, anywhere may express his or her beliefs, no matter how singular, without fear of being coerced into silence or conformity… Your legal concepts of property, expression, identity, movement, and context do not apply to us. They are all based on matter, and there is no matter here.” – Declaration of independence of Cyberspace – John Perry Barlow – Davos, 1996.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the world we live in today. Borders are hardening in our virtual world with the Great Firewall of China and the widespread emergence of Internet “clusters”. Many countries have attempted to turn off Internet services or to prevent free speech. Networks and algorithms turn us into data generators, influencing our daily habits and interests. It’s turning into a big AI-driven machine that commoditizes our lives, leaves the underserved behind and fails to provide sovereignty where we gather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. The technology that connects us is now used to distract, manipulate, polarize, divide and control the way we think, act and live our lives. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of people and IoT devices expected to join this broken digital world this decade, we have no choice but to heal our broken information ecosystem if we want to address the challenges we face collectively. So as we move towards a world where tech and science are merging together, how do we ensure a neutral, inclusive and regenerative digital future – one that truly serves humanity and eliminates the barriers that divide us?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer Internet incentivizes all citizens of our world to connect computers from their homes or offices to participate in a distributed data economy owned by the people. By allowing humans and machines to interweave without intermediaries, a decentralized and self-sovereign Internet can emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply – there is no good reason that our data is being stored and controlled by others in the information age. Why are we paying centralized companies to handle our information on our behalf, when it makes us vulnerable to be turned into products, and would take us the same time to do it ourselves?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer isn’t an alternative to the Internet, it’s an alternative to centralized cloud giants. The Internet doesn’t need replacing; it is one of the most beautiful inventions of our civilization, if not the greatest. Which is not to say that cloud providers are completely obsolete. They serve functions that decentralized systems cannot (e.g. big data); but peer-to-peer systems are just infinitely more resilient, secure, private and scalable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of exponential evolution and innovation, we have our fears around the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to disconnect ourselves even further from our reality and it is our responsibility to ensure a safe and fair future for the generations to come. A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential of technology to change the world remains endless and limited to our own imagination. We decide to switch from fear to love, and to move forward as one humanity. It is our responsibility as global citizens to pursue greater collective consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movement, a community of like-minded people that build the world of tomorrow!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;host the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Peer-to-Peer Overcomes Web3 Challenges</title>
		<published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-4/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2022/03/post-4/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First coined in 2014, Web3 is now one of the hottest and overused buzzwords in the digital space – the idea of a new iteration of the web, a decentralized environment based on blockchain technology that incorporates token-based economics. The promise of Web3 – decentralization of control and authority from big tech, data security, scalability, and privacy for users – is tremendous. But what is a promise without delivery? Is it possible that we will see major adoption soon?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thenewstack.io&#x2F;as-blockchain-hype-fades-developers-give-ethereum-a-serious-look&#x2F;&quot;&gt;enterprise blockchain hype&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that happened a few years ago, Web3 seems to be repeating the same story, with lots of chatter but lagging adoption. Millions have rushed to trade crypto and NFTs attached to Web3 – with a lot of this activity based on speculation and hype – but that doesn’t mean they will replace legacy platforms anytime soon. New approaches such as DeFi (decentralized finance) don’t have the same problem of the legacy firms, but they face the challenge of scaling and mass adoption. However, many so-called ‘Web3’ solutions are not as decentralized as they seem, and still have to show they are scalable, secure and accessible enough for the mass market. This all may change, but there are clear limitations that will need to be overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Web3 is a marketing slogan or a true technological trend, there is a lot of money and technology behind it. Financial institutions are embracing blockchain technology and we are seeing a rising adoption of digital assets across industries. While the idea of utilizing digital currencies to exchange different forms of value in an increasingly digital world certainly makes sense, it’s a bigger leap to say that blockchain alone can support a broad set of use cases, including replacing the current Internet infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet’s client-server infrastructure replicates data and workloads across many computers, and uses tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. However, the clear inefficiencies and gaps in security in today’s centralized infrastructures are being challenged by simpler means of building, storing and exchanging data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is a clear evolution to the centralized client-server model, but there are severe challenges sourced from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;certik&#x2F;the-blockchain-trilemma-decentralized-scalable-and-secure-e9d8c41a87b3&quot;&gt;blockchain trilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between decentralization, scalability and security. Peer-to-peer systems transcend those challenges as they don’t require any valid2ation or verification from a third party, and enable end-to-end connections that can scale limitlessly without the potential of being altered or corrupted by intermediaries. In peer-to-peer systems, all participants are equally privileged, presenting a fairer model. Peer-to-peer represents an incredibly simple and efficient paradigm for organizing our digital world, and has already proven to be the most efficient alternative to centralized information systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, there is no reason to replicate full sets of data and workloads across many computers, and use tons of computing resources and energy while limiting the scalability of our applications. While there is an increasing reliance on blockchain principles to organize our Internet systems, blockchain also makes things redundant, slow, complex and energy intensive. To be clear, blockchain isn’t the problem, as it is a great technology to store and exchange value in a decentralized way, but it is only one piece of the puzzle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By inter-connecting the computing processing power and storage capacity of billions of computers worldwide in a peer-to-peer way, data transfers could happen end-to-end between people and machines without the need to be verified. Peer-to-peer is also the only way to achieve a truly self-sovereign Internet – creating a ‘trustful’ environment that allows users and developers to have real data ownership.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems aren’t meant to replace blockchains – they represent a way to decentralize models that blockchain cannot, such as Internet infrastructures. Peer-to-peer systems and blockchains, side by side. The best of both worlds. Peer-to-peer as the most efficient and decentralized alternative for us to exchange data and Internet resources. And blockchain for establishing trust through an irrefutable record of transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of emerging technologies, a new technological foundation is needed to protect our sovereignty and freedom. The rise of blockchains, while well intended, ultimately has made the technological space more complex than ever before, and still benefits a plutocratic few (relative to its promise). More than just technology, peer-to-peer opens a world of new possibilities for humanity to co-initiate new paradigms and experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By applying blockchain and peer-to-peer technology to the cloud, ThreeFold solves the security and autonomy issues of the Internet and realizes the initial promise of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer, planetary mesh network of nodes owned by the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support the realization of a peer-to-peer Internet owned by the people today:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;Get TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;Connect a computer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the peer-to-peer Internet and earn monthly rewards.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&#x2F;manual__manual3_home_new&quot;&gt;Build applications&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Will Give Internet to 43% of the World’s Population</title>
		<published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/06/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/06/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations publicly ruled Internet access to be a human right in 2016. Proper access to the Internet helps to protect people’s freedom of speech and thought, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Nonetheless, as of 2019, about 43% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in access to information and knowledge. It is essential to take the necessary steps to strengthen the relationship between governments and people while still upholding all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold created an infrastructure that is easily affordable and jointly operated by network peers to make the modern Internet open and fair to everyone. Anybody with a network connection and electricity can add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. We&#x27;re looking for farmers around the globe and we&#x27;re also partnering with farming cooperatives to develop localized strategies and meet the specific needs of their region. Plus, the Foundation will incentivize and sponsor the extension and scope to areas that require Internet capacity the most, to ensure a fair and equitable delivery of the Internet to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Want to join the biggest internet revolution? &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farming.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Be part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of it, today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How You Can Join the People&#x27;s Internet</title>
		<published>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/06/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/06/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, that&#x27;s right. With ThreeFold, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; become the Internet! Let me quickly explain. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today&#x27;s Internet is powered by hyper-scale data centers which are owned by large corporations. With +80% of the global infrastructure and +60% of the global Internet networks owned by a bunch of companies, the Internet became a real business with us humans being the products of that business model.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold creates an entirely new Internet economy that is owned by all of us and makes the traditional cloud model of building data centers obsolete. With ThreeFold, independent people called &amp;quot;Farmers&amp;quot; plug in 3Nodes (hardware) from their homes or offices anywhere around the world. And they earn income for it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Together, they power a new, data-sovereign, and planet-positive Internet owned and powered by the people. This is a game-changer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-i-get-a-3node&quot;&gt;So, how do I get a 3Node?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can buy one of the ready-made nodes from cooperatives around the world. This is a good and very easy way to support the ThreeFold project and to &amp;quot;BE THE INTERNET.&amp;quot;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today you can buy a 3Node via our website. We are also working with our farming cooperatives to decentralize the provisioning and distribution of hardware to a glocal approach (a global network of local networks). 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what if 3Nodes are not immediately available? For example, last week we had a huge influx of orders for our Titan V2 3Nodes and sold out the entire batch with 3,000 extra orders. We&#x27;re now talking with many hardware distributors to make sure we can satsify all these orders, but this could take a while.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So if you are a little bit more adventurous, and want to build your 3Node from the ground up, yourself, here&#x27;s how to do it:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To &amp;quot;become the Internet&amp;quot; is fairly simple (but does take some technical knowledge and effort). Here&#x27;s what you&#x27;ll need:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with an INTEL or AMD brain, some memory, and some storage cabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A smartphone on which you can download and run the &amp;quot;ThreeFold Connect&amp;quot; app. This will provide you with a wallet (to receive your farmed TFT and to pay a very small amount of TFT to get started).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A laptop &#x2F; desktop (and USB stick) to launch your online 3Bot, configure your farm, download your bootloader and burn the bootloader to a USB stick.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some technical knowledge, interest and 45 minutes of time.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are still here and reading, we&#x27;re good to go! I go through the whole process in a 3-minute video which will give you a quick overview of how to set up your farm. (Click through to the video on YouTube and find helpful links in the description.)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;uxIZcsEsOUE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prefer a different format? We also have forum topics live about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;requirements-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;831&quot;&gt;the pre-requirements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-set-up-your-own-3node&#x2F;833&quot;&gt;how to set up your 3Node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (the steps I share in the video).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, thank you, thank you for reading this post and we hope to have you as part of our growing, global farming community. If you have any questions, please head to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or feel free to join us on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;our ThreeFold Farmer chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Telegram.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;@nickxshotz?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Nicholas Green&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold offers Data Sovereignty</title>
		<published>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/05/post-3/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/05/post-3/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=uaaC57tcci0&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you know all too well that today, people are being turned into products. Everything we do online – all of the data we upload and all of our digital activities – is tracked and oftentimes used against us. Targeted advertising is just the beginning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Personal data is used by algorithms to make incredible important decisions, like whether someone should receive financial or health support or benefits. In China, people are now even receiving “scores” for their behaviors. It sounds like Black Mirror, but it’s real life.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s the scary part. The good news is that things don’t have to be this way. ThreeFold is building the engine for an Internet where people can finally be data sovereign.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;today’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, infrastructure is centralized. Companies provide services in exchange for your personal data, which is stored on servers in hyper-scale data centers owned by private companies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In ThreeFold’s model, those servers are called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__3node&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and rather than sitting inside centralized data centers, they sit inside the homes or offices (or small data centers) owned by independent people and organizations called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro?id=what-is-3node&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But the data inside is owned by the person or persons who put it there. They maintain access right as well. From a technical standpoint, data is dispersed across 3Nodes by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;an algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that makes it such that nobody can access it. In addition, connections are peer-to-peer, meaning data goes directly between sender and recipient rather than passing through intermediaries as it does today – bringing further levels of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thus, people can finally be data sovereign, knowing their data is safe, and truly theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>We Need a More Inclusive Internet</title>
		<published>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/01/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2021/01/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, more than 40% of the world is without access to the internet, a tool which brings incredible access to knowledge (education) and important information, communication tools that keep loved ones connected and are crucial for emergencies, and economic opportunities. And over the last year, as the world is spending more time at home, digital economies are booming and education is going remote. With an uncertain future, we need to fix the digital divide or we risk leaving billions of people even further behind.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data-center-problem-cost-proximity&quot;&gt;The Data Center Problem: Cost &amp;amp; Proximity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The centralized data centers that power today&#x27;s Internet are located &amp;quot;strategically&amp;quot; mainly in North America, Europe, and select parts of Asia. For populations living in these regions, Internet is accessible and generally relatively affordable. But the further you travel from these data centers, the less available and more expensive the internet becomes. Internet access is mostly an issue Sub-saharan Africa, throughout Asia, and some parts of South America.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course some data centers can be and are being built in and near developing and remote regions, but for reasons including cost and audience, this hasn&#x27;t been a huge priority to date. Beyond that, the data center model as a whole simply cannot scale to meet the future demands of the internet nor is it sustainable for our planet, so this is not the right option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-internet-shutdown-problem-control-manipulation&quot;&gt;The Internet Shutdown Problem: Control &amp;amp; Manipulation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of internet access isn&#x27;t always just an availability or affordability problem. Today&#x27;s internet can be limited or even shut down at any point, by the right people. Take a quick look at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;netblocks.org&#x2F;reports&quot;&gt;NetBlocks.org&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an organization that reports on global internet disruptions or outages. Typically governments are enacting these measures during times of unrest or protest or  important political moments. Even in the United States, the Executive Branch of the government has &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.klemchuk.com&#x2F;ip-law-trends&#x2F;government-power-to-shut-down-the-internet&quot;&gt;the power to shut down the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a case of a national emergency.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Cutting the internet or restricting certain services based on region (a common practice as well) is not only not right, it&#x27;s dangerous. People rely on the internet for information and communication and no government or entity should have the ability to shut the internet down at their discretion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution-fair-neutral-internet-for-all&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution: Fair &amp;amp; Neutral Internet for All&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the United Nations declared internet access to be a human right, yet today if you are reading this post, you are privileged. All humans deserve access to the internet and ThreeFold has the solution.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With the ThreeFold model, nodes can be set up anywhere in the world where an existing internet connection and electricity are present. By putting physical infrastructure at the edge (close to users), greater levels of access can be reached.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, the ThreeFold Grid cannot be shut down or manipulated. It is a neutral internet owned by the people, where autonomous technology heals and runs itself and requires minimal human intervention.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today we are working with partners in the clean energy and network &#x2F; connectivity to build the solutions that are needed to provide fair and uninterrupted internet access with all corners of the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Of course we will need new safe, secure, and private solutions for people to collaborate online. Many of these are already live and deployable via ThreeFold Now Community Solutions. We are working with partners in the education space as well to build toolsets for students to enrich their lives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We need a more inclusive internet, and that is what we are building.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Is Peer-to-Peer and Why Is It so Important?</title>
		<published>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2020/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2020/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;What is Peer-to-Peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) is a term that originated from the distributed computer application architecture where tasks and workloads are shared between peers, popularized by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a revolutionary file storing system from the late 1990s.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The concept inspired new structures and philosophies in many areas of human interaction. P2P systems and groups are typically critical of authoritarian and centralized social structures and believe in equality, meritocracy, flat systems, participatory &amp;amp; circular economies, as the concept represents a concrete pathway to these outcomes or visions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
P2P systems are network, not linear or &#x27;pyramidal&#x27; hierarchies (though they may share some elements). They are &#x27;distributed&#x27;, though they may have elements of &#x27;centralization&#x27; and &#x27;decentralization.&#x27; And intelligence is not located at any center, but everywhere within the system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;How does ThreeFold relate to peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold&#x27;s Peer-to-Peer (P2P) computing network is a distributed architecture that splits tasks and workloads between its peers, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Farmers are equal participants in the network and together they form a peer-to-peer network of nodes, the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers make their resources, such as processing power, disk storage or network bandwidth, directly available to other network participants, without the need for central coordination by servers or stable hosts. Farmers are both suppliers and consumers of resources, in contrast to the traditional &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Client-server&quot;&gt;client-server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model in which the consumption and supply of resources is divided.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the near future, ThreeFold will create Digital Twin, which will go beyond the era of peers doing similar things while sharing resources. It will actually enable much more than that. Digital Twin will create a complete new digital world with diverse peers that can bring in unique resources and capabilities to a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_community&quot;&gt;virtual community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. This will empower the network of peers to engage in greater tasks beyond those that can be accomplished by individual peers, and are beneficial to all the peers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why did ThreeFold choose peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything starts (or should start) from the why, and the ThreeFold story started a long time ago. Before the inception of ThreeFold, many of the co-founders of the project used to work with the largest IT &amp;amp; Cloud actors. Throughout their experience working in the Industry, they realized that the complexity of the technology and the centralization of knowledge &amp;amp; power led to an inefficient, unsustainable, not scalable and unequally distributed infrastructure. So they decided to redesign the whole Internet and cloud infrastructure bottom-up with the vision of shaping a global internet economy that can scale anywhere efficiently, cost efficiently and sustainably.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Why does the world needs peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By developing the technology, the conviction that peer-to-peer was the best solution for humanity and the planet strengthened itself. Why? Well, put simply, a peer-to-peer system removes all forms of intermediaries, unnecessary steps and complexity from the picture. Therefore, it simplifies the architecture in an incredible way. The benefits are many but here are the most popular benefits:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Our peer-to-peer environment means no middlemen or intermediaries, meaning data travels directly between peers and stored on the nodes of their choice rather than being sent through and stored by a third party.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Data stored in data centers is susceptible to security breaches. In bypassing data centers and exchanging data directly between peers, we can achieve much greater security as it reduces code and back doors significantly.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: In a many-to-many system, scale is essentially unlimited. There is simply no bottleneck. And hardware (nodes) can be added at ease compared to current data center model.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-efficiency &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: End-to-end (direct) connection between peers means a more efficient path for data and less energy is needed. Less energy means less cost, and less harm to our planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;In 2021 the world is going peer-to-peer! &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;re now in 4 years into the project, and it is clear that ThreeFold holds the most advanced technology and is probably the only tech company in the world that can achieve a peer-to-peer network &amp;amp; digital world as envisioned by the concept authors. The ThreeFold Grid is running and already at it&#x27;s 2.4 version and 2021 will bring various commercial opportunities for the public to partake in the peer-to-peer network, from hosting IT workloads to experiencing P2P end-user solutions. In other words, in 2021, the world will be able to go peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>You Are Unique</title>
		<published>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2019/12/post-2/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2019/12/post-2/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-unique&quot;&gt;You are unique&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a gathering with some friends, I noticed something that made me think about how important it is what we’re doing at ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One of my friends was complaining about how he couldn’t log in to one of his social media platforms, because all of his passwords are different and he forgot which one he used for this particular platform. Another friend was saying how she tagged her sister on a funny meme, but her sister couldn’t find it on Facebook. Turns out she tagged her on Instagram. And then one of them said something that I keep hearing more and more from people, “Why do we have so many apps, I can’t find anything anymore!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We exist so many times online, but why? There is only one me in the real world. Why should there not be only one me online? Why should I have 25 different profiles on 25 different platforms, with 25 different logins, when I am unique?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That is another dilemma that ThreeFold has a solution for, with its autonomous technology. 3Bot - a digital avatar like no other, that basically handles your entire online life. The focus lies on digital privacy, where only you can access your data, and no one else. The 3Bot has all the functionalities you need to interact and exchange information and value, there will be no need for that many applications on your device anymore. With 3Bot, everything changes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The 3Bot is built on the ThreeFold Grid, and has the same values as ThreeFold. Freedom, Equality, and Sustainability. It is important that your data is safe, and what can be safer than you being the only one who not only has access to it, but also the only one who owns that data? Your online world should not be that different from your offline world. In your offline world, you are the center of your own life. That is what ThreeFold is doing with the 3Bot, putting you in the center of your online life, too.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
One decentralized application, one digital wallet, one login and one you. Because you’re unique.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Have questions? Feel free to ask us on our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Jessica Ruscello on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;DoSDQvzjeH0&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralizing the Internet</title>
		<published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2019/08/post-1/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.ourworld.tf/blog/2019/08/post-1/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, the Internet changed the world as we know it with the introduction of the World Wide Web. With time the Internet empowered people to share information in a decentralized way. Shortly after, big companies like Facebook, Google, and Apple emerged, providing many solutions that revolutionized the way we live. The “sharing economy” has grown exponentially over the last 5-10 years. This is thanks to a more simplified information flow and well-developed technology, which:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a much easier integration of independent players into the sharing economy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates the need for extensive management and structure of marketplace operators.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are entering a flat-structure economy. An economy where fewer managerial levels are needed for the system to function. New technologies such as blockchain and the Internet of Things facilitate this ongoing trend. Participants can now interact on a peer-to-peer basis, forming marketplaces and organizations according to pre-agreed, programmed contracts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;The current Internet is centralized&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the growth in popularity for decentralized systems, organizations, and currencies, the Internet remains centralized. The centralization within the Internet industry brought many barriers to entry. Indeed, to compete in the highly competitive market of Internet capacity dominated by big IT companies, massive investment, and IT development are needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what is really scary is that the current industry exploits the market tremendously. Data is officially the most valuable asset on earth for a few years, and about 20 companies rule over more than 80% of the cloud industry. In other words - these companies together have more than 80% of the world&#x27;s information. In recent years, we noticed the dangers that can arise with the wrong intentions within the data industry with the &#x27;Cambridge Analytica Scandal&#x27;, also highlighted in the movie &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&quot;&gt;&#x27;The Great Hack&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold has been developing technology that allows the decentralization of the Internet infrastructure - removing the need for data centers, and allowing anyone to take part in the Internet capacity market. Adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid (TF Grid) makes you a ThreeFold Farmer (TF Farmer). The more decentralized the Internet gets, the more secure and effective it will become. The already is the largest grid of compute and storage in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;How To Participate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a ThreeFold Farmer is very straightforward. Anyone can join the ThreeFold Grid by downloading the ThreeFold Zero-OS onto their nodes and connecting them to the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By doing this you will become an operator of a &amp;quot;micro data center&amp;quot; and with that earn ThreeFold Tokens. With or without experience in the field, anyone can become a ThreeFold Farmer. By becoming a ThreeFold Farmer, you empower a new neutral Internet that belongs to humanity - not corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can build your server (3node) and configure it, but also options for people with less technical knowledge are available. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&quot;&gt;pre-register.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see how easy it is for anyone to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blog written in 2019, updated January 2021.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
